Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- Carta particolare della parte Tramontana dell Isola di San Lorenza con la costa diripetto sin. a Monbazza con l'Isole e Seccagne Int. = East coast of Africa including the northern part of Madagascar. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0249; Copperplate: Uncolored; 45 cm. x 73 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The sea is decorated with one sailing vessel and a compass rose.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0249, p. 287
  Norwich number: 0249
  RID: MOA 0322
- Carta particolare che comincia con il fiume Juntas nella Guinea e finisce con il capo di S. Dara e con l'Isola d'S. Thomaso. = West coast of Africa from the river Juntas to Cape St. Dara. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0250; : Uncolored; 46 cm. x 74 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Island of St. Thomas.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0250, p. 287
  Norwich number: 0250
  RID: MOA 0321
- Carta particolare dell mare Oceano fra l'Ierlandia e l'Isole di Asores. = Chart of the western ocean with the Azores. -- Florence: Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649; Dudley, Robert, Sir, 1574-1649 Sea chart, 1646-7; NOR 0251; : Uncolored; 46 cm. x 36 cm.
  Source: Arcano del Mare
  Descriptive Notes: A compass rose and sailing vessel decorate the sea.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0251, p. 288
  Norwich number: 0251
  RID: MOA 0320
- Barbariae et Guineae Maritimi a Freto Gibralta ad Fluvium Gambiae cum Insulis Salsis Flandricis et Canaricis. = Sea chart of the Barbary and Guinea coasts from the Straits of Gibraltar to Cape Verde. -- Amsterdam: Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765; Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765 Sea chart, No date; NOR 0252; : Colored; 48 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map includes coast of Spain and Portugal. The sea shows several ships engaged in battle. Two compass roses radiate numerous rhumb lines. The cartouche illustrates a scene of a Moor holding a decapited head. Similar cartouche to van Keulen map (see NOR 0267).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0252, p. 289
  Norwich number: 0252
  RID: MOA 0222
  Oceans -- Sea chart -- 18th c.
- Tractus Littorales Guineae a Promontorio Verde usque ad Sinum Catenbelae. = Map of coast of Guinea from Cape Verde to Catenbela Bay. -- Amsterdam: Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765; Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765 Sea chart, No date; NOR 0253; : Colored; 49 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Sea contain three ships and two compass roses with rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0253, p. 290
  Norwich number: 0253
  RID: MOA 0221
  Oceans -- Guinea -- 18th c.
- Cimbebas et Caffariae Littora a Catenbela ad Promontorium Bonae Spei. Pascaerte van Cimbebas en Caffrares Streckende van Catembela tot Cabo de Bona Esperanca. = Map of Cimbebas and Caffraria from Catembela to Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: Renard, Louis; Renard, Louis Sea chart, 1715; NOR 0254; : Colored; 43 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Similar to Ottens map (see NOR 0255). Surrounding the cartouche is a group of lions, a leopard, goat and a snake. Lower corner, a group led by Neptune. Battling ships and two compass roses with rhumb lines decorate the Atlantic.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0254, p. 291
  Norwich number: 0254
  RID: MOA 0215
- Cimbebas et Caffariae Littora a Catenbela ad Promontorium Bonae Spei. Pascaert van Cimbebas en Caffrares Streckende van Catembela tot Cabo de Bona Esperanca. = Map of Cimbebas and Caffraria from Catembela to Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765; Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765 Sea chart, 1680-1745; NOR 0255; : Colored; 42 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Almost identical to the Renard's map (see NOR 0254). Inset: De Ommelanden van de Caap de Goede Hoop met de Saldanha, Tafel en Falso Baien in Groot Bestek.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0255, p. 292
  Norwich number: 0255
  RID: MOA 0218
- Cimbebas et Caffariae Littora a Catenbela ad Promontorium Bonae Spei. Pascaert van Cimbebas en Caffrares Streckende van Catembela tot Cabo de Bona Esperanca. = Map of Cimbebas and Caffraria from Catembela to Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765; Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765 Sea chart, 1680-1745; NOR 0255a; : Colored; 42 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Duplicate map. Almost identical to the Renard's map (see NOR 0254). Inset: De Ommelanden van de Caap de Goede Hoop met de Saldanha, Tafel en Falso Baien in Groot Bestek.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0255a, p. 292
  Norwich number: 0255a
  RID: MOA 0220
- Occidentalior Tractus Indiarum Orientalium a Promontorio Bonae Spei ad C. Comorin. = The Indian Ocean from Cape of Good Hope to Cape Comorin. -- Amsterdam: Wit, Frederik de; Wit, Frederik de Sea chart, 1680; NOR 0256; : Outline color; 44 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "One of four charts of the coast of Africa, that first appeared in Wit's Zee Atlas of 1675. Both Ottens and Renard appear to have adapted some of the plates for their own use." Cartouche includes several animals, a tiger, snake, lion, ostrich, and a cow. A group of figures stand on top of the title. Two compass roses radiate rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0256, p. 293
  Norwich number: 0256
  RID: MOA 0223
- Occidentalior Tractus Indiarum Orientalium a Promontorio Bonae Spei ad C. Comorin. = The Indian Ocean from Cape of Good Hope to Cape Comorin. -- Amsterdam: Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765; Ottens, R. (Reinier), 1698-1750; Ottens, J. (Josua), 1704-1765 Sea chart, 1680-1745; NOR 0257; : Colored; 44 cm. x 54 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: This map is identical to the Frederick de Wit's map (see NOR 0256).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0257, p. 294
  Norwich number: 0257
  RID: MOA 0216
- A Chart of Guinea Describing the Seacoast from Cape de Verde to Cape Bona Esperanca. -- London: Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698; Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698 Sea chart, 1675; NOR 0258; : Outline color; 43 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The chart appears in the English Pilot and the Altas Maritime (1675). A compass rose radiates rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0258, p. 295
  Norwich number: 0258
  RID: MOA 0239
- A Chart of Guinea. -- London: Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698; Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698, 1679; NOR 0259; : Outline color; 11 cm. x 14 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes a large compass rose with radiating rhumb lines. Inlets and bays are named.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0259, p. 296
  Norwich number: 0259
  RID: MOA 0186
- The Western Ocean. -- London: Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698; Seller, John, fl. 1658-1698 Sea chart, No date; NOR 0260; : Outline color; 43 cm. x 53 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map extends to include part of North and South America, western Europe and southern England. The cartouche, placed in the central Africa, contains two figures blowing horns. Another cartouche appears in South America with two natives and two animals surround the scale. The compass rose radiates rhumb lines to all four continents.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0260, p. 297
  Norwich number: 0260
  RID: MOA 0234
- Carte particuliere des Costes de l'Afrique depuis C. del Gado jusques Rio Mocambo, et les Isles aux Environs. Levee Par Ordre Expres de Roys de Portugal sous qui on en a Fait la Decouverte. = Specific map of the African coast from Cape del Gado to Rio Mocambo and the adjacent islands. -- Amsterdam: Mortier, Pierre; Mortier, Pierre Sea chart, 1700; NOR 0261; : Colored; 40 cm. x 58 cm.
  Source: Mortier's Atlas Suite de Neptune Francais or the Atlas Nouveau des Cartes Marines (1700)
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: L'Isle Anjoane ou Anjuanny. Sixteen-point compass rose radiates rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0261, p. 298
  Norwich number: 0261
  RID: MOA 0272
- Carte Particuliere de la Mer Rouge c. Levee Par Ordre Expres des Roys de Portugal, sous qui on en a Fait la Decouverte. = Specific map of the Red Sea. -- Amsterdam: Mortier, Pierre; Mortier, Pierre Sea chart, 1700; NOR 0262; : Outline color; 52.5 cm. x 76 cm.
  Source: Atlas Suite de Neptune Francais (1700)
  Descriptive Notes: The sea contains two compass roses with rhumb lines. Inset: Island of Zocatora, island and fort of Mombasa.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0262, p. 299
  Norwich number: 0262
  RID: MOA 0282
- Carte Particuliere des Costes de L'Afrique qui Comprend le Pays de Cafres c. Levee par Ordre Expres des Roys de Portugal sous qui on en a Fait la Decouverte. = Specific map of the African coast including Caffraria. -- Amsterdam: Mortier, Pierre; Mortier, Pierre Sea chart, 1700; NOR 0263; : Uncolored; 57 cm. x 82 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Indicates many rivers and settlements discovered by the Portuguese. The sea contains a sixteen-point compass rose with rhumb lines. Inset: Island of Inhancato and the fortress of Sofala.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0263, p. 300
  Norwich number: 0263
  RID: MOA 0283
- Carte Particuliere des Costes de l'Afrique depuis Cabo Ledo jusques au Cap de Bone Esperance. Levee par Ordre Expres des Roys de Portugal sous qui on en a fait la Decouvert. = Specific map of the African coast from Cape Ledo to the Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: Mortier, Pierre; Mortier, Pierre Sea chart, 1700; NOR 0264; : Colored; 58 cm. x 43 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The compass rose radiate rhumb lines. Inset: map of Saldanha Bay.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0264, p. 301
  Norwich number: 0264
  RID: MOA 0207
- Carte des Costes de L'Afrique depuis Cap de Lopo jusques a l'Isle Mazira. Levee par Ordre Expres des Roys de Portugal sous qui on en a Fait la Decouverte. = Map of the coast of Africa from Cape Lopo to the island of Mazira. -- Amsterdam: Mortier, Pierre; Mortier, Pierre Sea chart, 1700; NOR 0265; : Colored; 59 cm. x 48 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes portion of Arabia. Inset: Fortresse de Mozambique. Sea contain two compass roses with rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0265, p. 302
  Norwich number: 0265
  RID: MOA 0232
- Carte Particuliere des Costes du Cap de Bone Esperance c. Levee Par Ordre Expres des Roys de Portugal sous qui on en a Fait la Decouverte. = Map of the coast of the Cape of Good Hope ... -- Amsterdam: Mortier, Pierre; Mortier, Pierre Sea chart, 1700; NOR 0266; : Colored; 56 cm. x 80 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: View of the Cape of Good Hope. Plan of the Cape of Good Hope.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0266, p. 303
  Norwich number: 0266
  RID: MOA 0284
- Nieuwe Pascaert van Oost Indien Verthoonende hen van C. de Bona Esperanca tot aan het Landt van Eso. Geleyt op Wassende Graeden en van Veel Fouten Verbetert. = New map of East Indies from Cape of Good Hope to Japan and Australia. -- Amsterdam: Keulen, Johannes van; Keulen, Johannes van; Keulen, Johannes van Sea chart, 1680; NOR 0267; : Outline color; 51 cm. x 58 cm.
  Source: Zee Atlas (1680)
  Descriptive Notes: Two cartouches are shown on this map. The cartouche at the top is similar to Otten's map (see NOR 0252). The second cartouche provides the name and address of the author and is surrounded by dolphins and European traders. Two compass roses radiate rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0267, p. 304
  Norwich number: 0267
  RID: MOA 0236
- Pascaarte van de Bocht van Gabon tuschen C. Formosa and C. de Lopo. = Map of the coast of Gabon from Cape Formosa to Cape de Lopo. -- Amsterdam: Keulen, Johannes van; Keulen, Johannes van Sea chart, 1680; NOR 0268; : Colored; 50.5 cm. x 58.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes title on a piece of masonry, on each side are natives and apes. "The scale is illustrated on another rectangular stone block with the head and shoulders of a male and female leaning on the masonry." A ship, sea monster and a compass rose with numerous rhumb lines decorate the seas. Lower right: 6.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0268, p. 305
  Norwich number: 0268
  RID: MOA 0202
- A Plan of Table Bay with the Road of the Cape of Good Hope, from the Dutch Survey, Published by Johannes van Keulen. -- London: Robert Sayer and John Bennett (Firm); Keulen, Johannes van Sea chart, 1778; NOR 0269; : Uncolored; 48 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Also published in 1794, by Laurie and Whittle. A compass rose radiates numerous rhumb lines. Inset: South View of the Cape engraved by Abbe de la Caille. Top right: No. 3.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0269, p. 306
  Norwich number: 0269
  RID: MOA 0298
  Oceans -- Table Bay -- 18th c.
- A Plan of Table Bay, with the Road of the Cape of Good Hope, from the Dutch Survey, Published by Johannes van Keulen. -- 1778: Robert Laurie and James Whittle; Keulen, Johannes van Sea chart, London; NOR 0269a; : Uncolored; 48 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Almost identical map to NOR 0269, slightly larger and cartouche. Also published in 1794, by Laurie and Whittle. A compass rose radiates numerous rhumb lines. Inset: South View of the Cape engraved by Abbe de la Caille. Top right: No. 3.
  Norwich number: 0269a
  RID: MOA 0299
  Oceans -- Table Bay
- Wassende-Grade-Kaart van de Aetiopische Ocean beslooten met de kusten van Guinea, Angola, de Caffers en Brasilia. = Sea chart of the Atlantic Ocean with the coasts of Guinea, Angola, Caffraria and Brazil. -- Amsterdam: Joannes van Keulen, over de Nieubrug in de Gekroonde Lootsman; Keulen, Johannes van; Keulen, Johannes van Sea chart, 1753?; NOR 0270; : Colored; 51 cm. x 59 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "The west coast of Africa is accurately depicted with its numerous Portuguese-named harbours." The compass rose radiates numerous rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0270, p. 308
  Norwich number: 0270
  RID: MOA 0288
- A chart of the coast of Africa from Mozambique to the Straits of Babelmandel and the adjoyning Ocean. -- London: Knapton, James, d. 1738; Knapton, John, 1696-1770; Knapton, James, d. 1738; Knapton, John, 1696-1770 Sea chart, 1728; NOR 0271; : Uncolored; 48 cm. x 58 cm.
  Source: Atlas Maritimus et Commercialis (1728)
  Descriptive Notes: Chart includes the Horn of Africa and numerous islands in the Indian Ocean. The compass roses radiate numerous rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0271, p. 309
  Norwich number: 0271
  RID: MOA 0038
  Oceans -- Eastern Africa -- 18th c.
- Carte Reduite de la Cote Meridionale d'Afrique, depuis Ia Baye de Saldagne jusqu'au Cap des Courans ... = Map of southern coast of Africa from Saldanha Bay to Cape Courans ... -- Amsterdam:; Mortier, Pierre; Jaillot, Jean Baptiste Michel, 1710?-1780 Sea chart, 1775; NOR 0272; : Uncolored; 48 cm. x 66.5 cm.
  Source: Atlas Neptune Oriental (1775)
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Plan de la Baye St. Blaise. Plan de la Baye de Formose ou Mossel-Baye. Plan de la Bay de Lagoa. Top right: 11.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0272, p. 310
  Norwich number: 0272
  RID: MOA 0285
- A Generall Chart from England to Cape Bona Espranca with the Coast of Brasile. -- London: R. Mount T. Page (Firm); Mount, William; Page, Thomas Sea chart, No date; NOR 0273; : Colored; 53 cm. x 43.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The compass rose radiates numerous rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0273, p. 311
  Norwich number: 0273
  RID: MOA 0233
- The Bay of Algoa on the South Coast of Africa; Plan of Mossel Bay on the South Coast of Africa; Plan of Flesh Bay or Bay St. Bras on the South Coast of Africa; from van Keulen. -- London: Robert Sayer and John Bennett (Firm); Keulen, Johannes van Sea chart, 1778; NOR 0274; : Uncolored; 58 cm. x 26 cm
  Descriptive Notes: Three sea charts includes soundings and rhumb lines of the South Coast of Africa. Bottom right: No. 4.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0274, p. 312
  Norwich number: 0274
  RID: MOA 0289
- Pascaert van de Costa de Caffres Tusschen Cabo Negro en Cabo de bonae Esperanca. = Map of the coast of Kaffraria between Cape Negro and the Cape of Good Hope. -- Amsterdam: R. Mount T. Page (Firm); Mount, William; Page, Thomas, 1716; NOR 0275; : Colored; 50 cm. x 58 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The sea contains two compass roses with numerous rhumb lines extending over the mainland, one sailing vessel and one sea monster. Inset: Saldanha Bay. Bottom right: 9.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0275, p. 313
  Norwich number: 0275
  RID: MOA 0273
  Africa -- Sea chart -- 18th c.
- Plan du Cap de Bonne-Esperance et de ses Environs. = Map of the Cape of Good Hope and its surroundings. -- Paris: Haye, G. de la; Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis, 1707-1780 Sea chart, 1752; NOR 0276; : Colored; 48 cm. x 33 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Near the coastline, soundings in French fathoms. Top right: 8.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0276, p. 314
  Norwich number: 0276
  RID: MOA 0077
  Oceans -- Cape of Good Hope -- 18th c.
- A Chart of the Coast of Africa from Cape Virde to Cape to Cape Bona Esperance. -- London: R. Mount T. Page (Firm) Sea chart, 1708; NOR 0277; : Colored; 44 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "The coastal placenames are numerous and based on Portuguese discoveries and exploration." The sea contains a compass rose with rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0277, p. 315
  Norwich number: 0277
  RID: MOA 0275
- A chart of the Western part of the East Indies with all the Adjacent Islands from Cape Bona Esperanca to the Island of Ceylon. -- London: R. Mount T. Page (Firm); Mount, William; Page, Thomas Sea chart, 1708; NOR 0278; : Colored; 44 cm. x 56 cm.
  Source: Atlas Maritimus
  Descriptive Notes: Companion chart (see NOR 0277). Originally published by John Seller. Two compass roses radiate rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0278, p. 316
  Norwich number: 0278
  RID: MOA 0208
- Carte Reduite d'une partie des costes occidentales et meridionales de l'afrique depuis Cabo Frio ou Cap Froid par les 19 degres de latitude merid. jusqu'a la baye S. Blaise pour servir aux vaissaux de la francais ... par ordre de M. Rouille ... = Map of southwest coast of Africa from Cap Froid to the Bay of St. Blaise. -- Paris: Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772 Sea chart, 1754; NOR 0279; : Colored; 89 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Five editions of this chart were printed. Inset: Views of Cape of Good Hope, Cape Agulhas and False Bay headland; Prime meridian through Paris, Ferro Island, Tenerife, Cap Lezard and London. Top right: 90.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0279, p. 317
  Norwich number: 0279
  RID: MOA 0090
  Oceans -- Southwest coast of Africa -- 18th c.
- Carte reduite de l'ocean oriental ou mer des indes ... par ordre de M. de Machault ... = Map of the Indian Ocean. -- Paris: Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772 Sea chart, 1757; NOR 0280; : Colored; 55 cm. x 86 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The large cartouche is illustrated with trees, foliage, an elephant and a crocodile. Numerous rhumb lines radiate over the mainland; Prime meridian through Ferro Island and Tenerife.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0280, p. 318
  Norwich number: 0280
  RID: MOA 0091
  Oceans -- Indian Ocean -- 18th c.
- Vue de la Baye de False. Vue de la Rade de Simons-Baye. = View of False Bay. View of the roadstead in Simon's Bay. -- Paris: Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis d', 1707-1780; Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis d', 1707-1780 Sea chart, 1775; NOR 0281; : Colored; 47 cm. x 33 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Five silhouettes (Cape Agulhas, Cape of Hottentots, Cape of Good Hope, and two views of False Bay) on one sheet. Top right: 8.2d.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0281, p. 319
  Norwich number: 0281
  RID: MOA 0078
  Oceans -- False Bay and Simon's Bay -- 18th c.
- Plan de la Baye Simon, Situe au Cap de Bonne Esperance, suivant les Observations faites en Aout et Septembre 1775, par Mr. Dalrymple. = Plan of Simon's Bay at the Cape of Good Hope. -- Paris: Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis d', 1707-1780; Apres de Mannevillette, Jean-Baptiste-Nicolas-Denis d', 1707-1780 Sea chart, NOR 0282; : Colored; 45 cm. x 33 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Apres de Mannevillette "was the first to determine longitude by measuring the distances of the sun and moon." Soundings are in French fathoms. Top right: 8.d.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0282, p. 320
  Norwich number: 0282
  RID: MOA 0079
  Oceans -- Simon's Bay -- 18th c.
- A map and chart of the Cape of Good Hope, with the Soundings in Table Bay, False Bay, and Saldanha Bay. -- London: Bew, John, d. 1793; Bew, John, d. 1793; Bew, John, d. 1793 Sea chart, 1781; NOR 0283; : Colored; 37.5 cm. x 27.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Published by Bew in 1781 as the English edition of Apres de Mannevillette's map in 1775. The sea contains a single compass rose.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0283, p. 321
  Norwich number: 0283
  RID: MOA 0095
- A Plan of Cape Bona Esperance with False Bay. -- London: Robert Laurie and James Whittle; Huddart, Joseph, 1741-1816 Sea chart, 1794; NOR 0284; : Uncolored; 66 cm. x 46 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: This chart also appeared in editions of Sayer and Bennett's Oriental Pilot. Inset: Silhouettes of mountain ranges from Table Mountain to Seamensberg. The bay contains a compass rose radiating rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0284, p. 322
  Norwich number: 0284
  RID: MOA 0303
- Tabula Moderna Prime Partis Aphricae. = Modern map of first part of Africa. -- Strasbourg: Schott, Johann, 1477-1548; Waldseemuller, Martin, 1470-1521?, 1513; NOR 0286; : Colored; 41 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Companion map to NOR 0149. Many kingdoms and coastal names are stated.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0286, p. 325
  Norwich number: 0286
  RID: MOA 0330
  Africa -- Northern Africa -- 16th c.
- [North Africa]. -- Lyons: Trechsel, Melchior, fl. 1529-1549; Trechsel, Gaspard, fl. 1529-1549; Ptolemy, 2nd cent., 1535; NOR 0287; Woodcut: Uncolored; 29 cm. x 44 cm.
  Source: Clavdii Ptolemaei Alexandrini Geographicae Enarrationis Libri Octo.
  Descriptive Notes: Map shaped irregular. Volume edited by Michael Servetus or Villanovanus.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0287, p. 326
  Norwich number: 0287
  RID: MOA 0039
- Aphricae Tabula II. = Map of North Africa. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1544; NOR 0289; Woodcut: Uncolored; 25 cm. x 33 cm.